Privacy Policy
==============

Last updated: August 1st, 2024

CrankWheel ehf. (“us”, “we”, or “our”) operates the http://crankwheel.com/, http://syna.is/ and http://meeting.is/ websites (the “Service”).

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information when you use our Service.

We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.

**We use your data for providing and improving the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.** Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, accessible at http://crankwheel.com/

**CrankWheel is compliant with the EU’s [General Data Protection Regulation](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/?uri=CELEX%3A32016R0679)**. You can read more about our policies and how to exercise your rights under the GDPR by reading our [Data Protection Statement](https://crankwheel.com/data-protection) which shall be an integral part of this Privacy Policy.

**Information Collection And Use**

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you. Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to, your email address, name, other information (“Personal Information”).

The CrankWheel web application, optionally assisted by a browser extension for Microsoft Edge, Google Chrome or other browsers, collects and transmits snapshots of your screen, application window, web-cam or browser tab, upon your request. These snapshots are never stored for longer than required to transmit them to your viewers, are not written to disk, and are transmitted only over encrypted communication channels.

For users of the optional add-on features audit logging and content filter, the optional CrankWheel browser extension captures and transmits to our servers the URLs of web pages you screen share.

The use of information received from Google APIs will adhere to the Chrome Web Store User Data Policy, including the Limited Use requirements.

**Personal Information**

Our web servers collect information that your browser sends whenever you visit our Service (“Log Data”). This Log Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages and other statistics.

When you initiate or participate in a screen sharing session using our application, our servers collect information transmitted by the application that includes your computer’s Internet Protocol ((“IP”)) address, browser type, browser version, the time and date of your visit, the time spent in a screen sharing session and other statistics. If you are a registered user of CrankWheel, certain personally identifiable information is stored in our systems such as your email address, and possibly your name, title and an uploaded photo. If you are participating only as a viewer of a screen sharing session, all personally identifiable data is depersonalized before it is stored (for example, we do not store full IP addresses or phone numbers, removing enough information to depersonalize them), with one exception; if you are sent a text message to join a screen sharing session, your phone number as entered by the presenter is shared with our text messaging provider, Twilio, which retains your phone number for up to 10 days. The log data stored by CrankWheel itself contains no personal information.

In addition, we may use third party services such as Google Analytics that collect, monitor and analyze anonymous usage information in order to increase our Service’s functionality. These third party service providers have their own privacy policies addressing how they use such information.

**Cookies**

Cookies are files with small amount of data, which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a web site and stored on your computer’s hard drive.

We use “cookies” make your browsing through our web site more attractive and easy and for collecting statistical data on the web site. You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.

We use the services of Google Analytics and Amplitude in order to analyze traffic through our web site and application, without processing information on identifiable individuals.

**Service Providers**

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service, to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

**Communications**

We may use your Personal Information to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send or by contacting us.

**Compliance With Laws**

We will disclose your Personal Information where required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that such action is necessary to comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement or to protect the security or integrity of our Service.

**Business Transaction**

If CrankWheel ehf. is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, your Personal Information may be transferred. We will provide notice before your Personal Information is transferred and becomes subject to a different Privacy Policy.

**Security**

The security of your Personal Information is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

All communication between our application and our web servers is encrypted using TLS.

All our processing of Personal Information is subject to appropriate technical and organisational measures designated by us.

**International Transfer**

Your information, including Personal Information, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

**Links To Other Sites**

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over, and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

**Children’s Privacy**

Our Service is not intended for processing of personal information on a data subject under the age of 13 (“Child”).

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Child has provided us with Personal Information, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

**Changes To This Privacy Policy**

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by emailing [support@crankwheel.com](mailto:support@crankwheel.com) or calling us at +1 (877) 753-2945.
